Guide to the RISM Audiovisual Collection RISM.RG.18
New York University Archives
Audiovisual Collection of the Research Institute for the Study of Man
1957-1996
New York University Archives
Research Institute for the Study of Man
RISM.RG.18
2.5 Linear Feet
These tapes are not obviously part of any other RISM collections. They include 1/4" audio as well as cassette tapes. There are commercially produced music tapes in the collection as well.
Provenance
These materials were transferred from the Research Institute for the Study of Man.
Access Restrictions
Some of the materials in this collection may be restricted. Please contact the University Archives with questions.
Additionally, please note that this collection is stored offsite, and you must contact the repository to schedule access.
Separated Material
The following tapes have been appended to specific collections:
The Vera D. Rubin Papers, 1955 - 1985 (RG1)
"Jamaican Pot Study/Dr. Rubin"
Producer: Mark Schorr WSRF/WSHE-FM
Nov 1973
Dr. Vera Rubin
Cannabis Congress Report Chicago
undated
Ganja in Jamaica by Vera Rubin w/comments by Cora Weiss (7.5")
Sep 1975
Michael Manley @ Seton Hall
undated
Papers The Untold Story -- Chronicle in the words of Maurice Bishop, with added commentary by Charles Shultz, Ron Dellums and others. Edited and produced by Felipe Sigidi Braudy with Estrella Mar, Inter-American Communications Foundation.
Dec 1984
Ganja -- A discussion with Jon Lomberg, Toronto, Canada,
Jul 11, 1980
CBC Marijuana: Commissions and Culture
John Chappel, Vera Rubin, Louis Bozzetti, Mel Green
undated
Sula Benet Papers (RG2)
Aging from Birth to Death: Biosocial Perspectives. Recorded presentations by the following speakers: Gerald E. McClearn, James F. Fries, J. Allan Herd, Richard Suzman, Judith Rodin
The Jamaica Peace Corps Training Project, 1961 - 62 (RG 6)
Louise Bennett: Jamaican Folklore Peace Corps Jamaica Training Program International House, New York 5/28/62 -- 7" reel-to-reel tape
Peace Corps. Graduation Ceremonies International House (3 tapes) 5/30/62 -- 7" reel-to-reel tape
VR res. Miss Lane, Peace Corps. Contracts Div., Wash., D.C. 7" reel-to-reel tape
Language Guide to Jamaica 2 of 3 reels 7" reel-to-reel tape
Language Guide to Jamaica 3 of 3 reels 7" reel-to-reel tape
Jamaican Creole Language Guide by Beryl Bailey 2 cassette tapes
Dr. Bertram Schaffner's Second Lecture
May 1962
Mr. & Mrs. Robert Ragsdale
Allen Gray Show, C.B.S. Mrs. [Eleanor] Roosevelt
May 1962
Peace Corp. - Studyman Bolivia U.S. Peace Corps. 1964 - 1968 (RG 9)
Side 2: Story 1; Side 1: Story 2
May 1962
Conference and Symposium Papers, (RG 16)
(5" reel -- no box)
undated
S.A.A. Conference Mexico
[1969?]
Haiti Conference
Tape 1A & B -- 5" reel
Tape 1A & B -- 5" reel
Tape 3A & B -- 5" reel
Tape 4A & B -- 5" reel
Tape 5A & B -- 5" reel
Tape 6A only -- 5" reel
Nov 1967
Valdmer, Berry & Elementary Education
Folkways Guillaime Both sides -- 7" tape
RISM Conference and Symposium Papers, RG 16 (cont.)
New Perspectives on Caribbean Studies: Toward the 21st Century
Nationalism, Independence and Creative
Floresence (Side B + 2 tapes)
undated
Theoretical and applied issues in Social Organization (2 tapes)
Aug 29, 1984
Stratification, pluralism and sociopolitical
Dynamics (3 tapes)
Aug 29, 1984
Theoretical and Applied Issues in Social
Organization (Side A)
[Aug 1984?]
Caribbean Conference
Processing Ethnicity (3 tapes)
Aug 30, 1984
Health in the Caribbean and Central America (3 tapes)
Aug 31, 1984
Public Health Indices of Development
(Side A)
Aug 31, 1984
Regional and Intra-Haitian Migration
(Side B + 2 tapes)
undated?
Political Economy and Sociocultural Change (3 tapes)
Aug 31, 1984
Agriculture and New Technologies
Dependency and Self-reliance (2 tapes)
Aug 31, 1984
Political Economy of the Caribbean Basin
Integration (2 tapes)
Sep 1, 1984
Caribbean Basin: Crisis, Reaction and
Response (4 tapes)
Sep 1, 1984
Audiotapes.; Research Institute for the Study of Man
- I. Reel-to-reel Tapes (unknown provenance), 1955-1985
  - Calypso in Trinidad- 7" Reel, June 1957; cuid27 (Box 1, Item 1)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    1/4'' open reel
    Scope and Contents note
    On case: "Calypso in T'dad; 6/7/57; Last cut at 7 1/2 IPS; Trinidad Salutes Assignment; Vocal by March of Dimes"
  - "Sparrow Power" recorded in Port of Spain, Trinidad - 7" Reel, undated; cuid28 (Box 1, Item 2)
    On Case: "Side A (Sparrow = Slinger Francisco); Recorded in Post of Spain, Tr." Track List: 1) Panman, 2) Grampa's Advice, 3) Sweeter Than You, 4) Learn to Cook, 5) Shake Your Waist, 6) Sell the Pussy, 7) Wilhemena, 8) Saturday Night, 9) Chinese Love Affair, 10) Dutch Romance"
  - King Eric and His Knights at the Big Bamboo in Bay Street, Nassau/Bahamas - 7" Reel, undated; cuid29 (Box 1, Item 3)
    On case: "Side A: King Eric and His Knights at the Big Bamboo-1) Limbo Rock, 2) Watermelon on the Vine, 3) Dinasoar, 4) Nassau Market, 5) These are the Times, 6) Fools Rush In, 7) Big Bamboo Bama, 8) Mambo Jambo, 9) Do You Love Me, 10) Uncue You, 11) I Adore Her, 12) Big Bamboo; The Treasure Cove (Rising Sun) Steel Band-Solid Steel- 1) 67, 2) Guantanamera, 3) Watermelon Man, 4) Poor Old Joe, 5) Fire in Your Wire; Side B: Solid Steel Cont.- 1) Governor's Ball (written by Sparrow), 2) Blue Danube, 3) No Money No Love, 4) Sound of Music, 5) Pany Boy, 6) Sandra (written by Sparrow); "Beauty and the Brute Force"- 1) J.B. Williams Road March, 2) Cha Cha Mambo, 3) Woman in Love, 4) Fire Down Below, 5) Zambezi, 6) Breakfast in Bed (Calypso), 7) Calypso Blues, 8) Balisier, 9) Que Sera, Sera, 10) Jamaica Farewell, 11) Banna Song, 12) Autumn Leaves"
  - Dave Gardner, "Kick thy Own Self" and "Rejoice Dear Hearts" - 7" Reel, undated; cuid30 (Box 1, Item 4)
    On case: "Side 1-Dave Gardner: 'Kick Thy Own Self' (Lost Left Channel on Side 2 of Record); 'Rejoice Dear Hearts'" Commercially Released
  - Dave Gardner, continuation of "Rejoice Dear Hearts," "Did You Ever" - 7" Reel, undated; cuid31 (Box 1, Item 5)
    On case: "Dave Gardner, Side 1: Continuation of 'Rejoice Dear Hearts' start of 'Did You Ever' Side 2: Rest of 'Did You Ever'" Commercially Released
  - Otis Redding/Carla Thomas, "King and Queen," "History of Otis Redding," The Peanut Butter Conspiracy is Spreading, The Other Half - 7" Reel, undated; cuid32 (Box 1, Item 6)
    On case: "Side One: Otis Redding/Carla Thomas, 'King & Queen'; Otis Redding, 'History of Otis Redding'; Side Two: The Peanut Butter Conspiracy, 'Is Spreading'; 'The Other Half'"; Commercially Released
  - Martha Jean Claude - 7" Reel, undated; cuid33 (Box 1, Item 7)
    On tape: "Destine, M. Jean Claude"
  - Songs at Veiquoix I of II - 7" Reel, undated; cuid34 (Box 1, Item 8)
    On index card: "The suffering of Christ" and various other illegible notes
  - Songs at Veiquoix II of II - 7" Reel, undated; cuid35 (Box 1, Item 9)
  - Alfred - 7" Reel, undated; cuid36 (Box 1, Item 10)
    On tape: "Alf-Outs; Oct. 12"
  - Guillaume - 7" Reel, undated; cuid37 (Box 1, Item 11)
  - Folkways, Guillaume - 7" Reel, undated; cuid38 (Box 1, Item 12)
    On case: "Folkways, Guillaume; Monophonic; Both Sides"
  - Alfred - Reel #1 re-record - 7" Reel, undated; cuid39 (Box 1, Item 13)
    On tape: "Alf-Ots"
  - Dave Gardner - "All Seriousness Aside," "It Don't Make No Difference" - 7" Reel, undated; cuid40 (Box 1, Item 14)
    On case: "Side 1-Dave Gardner: "All Seriousness Aside (Poor Recording); Side 2-"It Don't Make No Difference"; Commercially Released
  - Untitled - 7" Reel, undated; cuid41 (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Geno Washinton and the Ram Jam Band "Funky-Butt Live!," The Hombres "Let It Out," Paul Revere and the Raiders "Greatest Hits," Spencer Davis "Greatest Hits" - 7" Reel, undated; cuid42 (Box 1, Item 16)
    On Case: "Side One-Geno Washinton and the Ram Jam Band, "Funky-Butt Live!"; The Hombres, "Let It Out"; Side Two-Paul Revere and the Raiders, "Greatest Hits"; Spencer Davis, "Greatest Hits"; Commercially Released
  - Spanish Music - 7" Reel, undated; cuid43 (Box 1, Item 17)
    Phyiscal Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
  - Bach Goldberg Variations- 7" Reel, undated; cuid44 (Box 1, Item 18)
    Commercially Released
  - Lucius Delany, Mayme Richardson- 7" Reel, undated; cuid45 (Box 1, Item 19)
    On case: "Do Not Erase; Leo Levy 1560 Grand Conc. Bronx 57, N.Y."
  - Bato 2-3 - 7" Reel, undated; cuid46 (Box 1, Item 20)
    On case: Bartok Concert??"; Commercially Released
  - Untitled - 7" Reel, undated; cuid47 (Box 1, Item 21)
    Case possibly reads: "Buffalo? Quartet, m.2 12/34"
  - Untitled - 7" Reel, undated; cuid48 (Box 1, Item 22)
    On case: "Poe"
  - Untitled - 7" Reel, undated; cuid49 (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Untitled - 7" Reel, undated; cuid50 (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Untitled - 7" Reel, undated; cuid51 (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Untitled - 7" Reel, undated; cuid52 (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Untitled - 7" Reel, undated; cuid53 (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Untitled - 7" Reel, undated; cuid54 (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Untitled - 5" Reel, undated; cuid55 (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Bikel - Digging the Weans - 5" Reel, undated; cuid56 (Box 1, Item 30)
    On case: "Mel Zuck AFSC; 6.14.70"
  - Untitled - 5" Reel, undated; cuid57 (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Untitled - 5" Reel, undated; cuid58 (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Untitled - 5" Reel, undated; cuid59 (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Untitled - 5" Reel, undated; cuid60 (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Untitled - 5" Reel, undated; cuid61 (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Untitled - 8mm Reel, undated; cuid62 (Box 1, Item 36)
    8 mm
  - Untitled - 8mm Reel, undated; cuid63 (Box 1, Item 37)
- II. Audio and Video Cassettes (unknown provenance), 1969-1979
  - Alister Hughes Barbados Interview and Press Conference - Microcassette, October 27; cuid64 (Box 2, Item 1)
    On case: "Small amount of Alister Hughes Barbados Press Conference"
    Microcassette
  - Untitled- 272 Cassette Tape, undated; cuid65 (Box Shared University Archives 098, Item 2)
    Audiocassette
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    This tape was not transferred because it is blank.
  - Saucier Part I, undated; cuid66 (Box 3, Item 3)
  - Untitled - 272 Cassette Tape, undated; cuid67 (Box 3, Item 4)
  - Untitled - 272 Cassette Tape, undated; cuid68 (Box 3, Item 5)
  - Norman Manley: A Jamaican Hero - A Docudrama by Trevor Rhone, 1993; cuid69 (Box 2, Item 6)
    Double Disc Set
    Audio CD
  - La Bamba Demonstration Tape - Cassette Tape, undated; cuid70 (Box 3, Item 7)
    On tape: "For Demonstration"
  - La Bamba Demonstration Tape - Cassette Tape, undated; cuid71 (Box 3, Item 8)
    Scope and Contents
  - Carriacou By Alan Lomax and Carol King (1 of 2) - Video Cassette, February 1991; cuid72 (Box 2, Item 9)
    On tape: "Carriacou by Allen Lomax and Carole Kulig; Copyright Association for Cultural Equity, 450 W. 41st St., NY, NY, 10036; 1 of 2"; SP
    VHS
  - Carriacou By Alan Lomax and Carol King (2 of 2) - Video Cassette, February 1991; cuid73 (Box 2, Item 10)
    On tape: "Carriacou by Allen Lomax and Carole Kulig; Copyright Association for Cultural Equity, 450 W. 41st St., NY, NY, 10036; 2 of 2"; SP
  - Carriacou Boat Launching Uned., E. Frankenstein, R. Goddard, M. Deutsch - Video Cassette, April 16-17, 1988; cuid74 (Box 2, Item 11)
    On case: "Carriacou Boat Launching Uned., E. Frankenstein, R. Goddard, M. Deutsch"
  - Trinidad: Memories of Carnival 1990 - Video Cassette, cuid75 (Box 2, Item 12)
    On paper insert: "Paul Martin, EP Productions"
  - Trinidad: Memories of Carnival 1990 - Video Cassette, cuid76 (Box 2, Item 13)
  - Trinidad: Memories of Carnival 1990 - Video Cassette, cuid77 (Box 2, Item 14)
  - Trinidad: Memories of Carnival 1990 - Video Cassette, cuid78 (Box 2, Item 15)
  - Trinidad: Memories of Carnival 1990 - Video Cassette, cuid79 (Box 2, Item 16)
  - Trinidad: Memories of Carnival 1990 - Video Cassette, cuid80 (Box 2, Item 17)
  - Trinidad: Memories of Carnival 1990 - Video Cassette, cuid81 (Box 2, Item 18)
  - Caribbean Eye (1 of 4) - Video Cassette, 1996; cuid82 (Box 2, Item 19)
    Thirteen Part Series: 1) Community Celebrations (other Caribbean Festivals), 2) Indigenous Survivors, 3) Musique Antillean, 4) Pan Caribbean; Banyan Productions
  - Caribbean Eye (2 of 4) - Video Cassette, 1996; cuid83 (Box 2, Item 20)
    Thirteen Part Series: 5) Dramatic Actions, 6) Talk and More Talk, 7) Independent Voices, 8) Women in Action; Banyan Productions
  - Caribbean Eye (3 of 4) - Video Cassette, 1996; cuid84 (Box 2, Item 21)
    Thirteen Part Series: 9) Caribbeam Carnivals, 10) Visionaries, 11) Games We Play; Banyan Productions
  - Caribbean Eye (4 of 4) - Video Cassette, 1996; cuid85 (Box 2, Item 22)
    Thirteen Part Series: 12) Soca-Soul to Sale, 13) Film Caribbean; Banyan Productions
  - "51" - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid86 (Box 3, Item 23)
  - Untitled - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid87 (Box 3, Item 24)
  - Abkhasia, Inal-Opa, and Paula Okapodat Kaptaza - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid88 (Box 3, Item 25)
  - 4 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid89 (Box 3, Item 26)
  - Tbkisi, Georgia and Tbilisi, Nella - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid90 (Box 3, Item 27)
  - Carriacou Recordings by Alan Lomax - Audio Cassette, 1962; cuid91 (Box 3, Item 28)
    On case: "Recordigns made by Alan Lomax in Carriacou, 1962--gift to the Institute for the Stude of Man, not to be copied (except for in-house use) or published without the donor's permission"
  - NBG and Grenada, Sea Moon, Maurice Bishop - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid92 (Box 3, Item 29)
  - Untitled - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid93 (Box 3, Item 30)
  - Untitled - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid94 (Box 3, Item 31)
  - Grenada, The Untold Story in the Words of Maurice Bishop - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid95 (Box 3, Item 32)
    On case: "Grenada…'The Untold Story,' An audio chronicle in the words of Maurice Bishop, with Eugenia Reagan, Charles Shultz, Ron Dellums, and others. Edited and Produced by Felipe Sigidi Braudy with Estrella del Mar. Inter-American Communications Foundation; Made eclusively for Vera Rubin. Love Daniel 12/84"
  - Alimenta Bishop, November 3, 1983; Barbados Phone-In Programme; News Young Socialist League; Reaction around the Caribbean - Audio Cassette, cuid96 (Box 3, Item 33)
  - RFG News - Fort Rupert Killing; Announcement of appointment of new cabinet by Rwdutam Council; Jamaican Voice and counterrevolution - Audio Cassette, 1983; cuid97 (Box 3, Item 34)
  - 2 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid98 (Box 3, Item 35)
  - 57 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid99 (Box 3, Item 36)
  - 8 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid100 (Box 3, Item 37)
  - Alinienta Bishop 10 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid101 (Box 3, Item 38)
  - 3 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid102 (Box 3, Item 39)
  - Untitled - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid103 (Box 3, Item 40)
  - Untitled - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid104 (Box 3, Item 41)
  - 519 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid105 (Box 3, Item 42)
  - Mass O. Therapist and News Bulletin, Sports News, Denial of False Rumors, PRA Announcement, Black, News, Radio Meetings, Black - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid106 (Box 3, Item 43)
  - Blank 6 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid107 (Box 3, Item 44)
  - 13 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid108 (Box 3, Item 45)
  - Untitled - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid109 (Box 3, Item 46)
  - Carry Cordier 150 Norelco Demonstration Tape - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid110 (Box 3, Item 47)
  - Untitled - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid111 (Box 3, Item 48)
  - 56 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid112 (Box 3, Item 49)
  - S20 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid113 (Box 3, Item 50)
  - Lectures on 3 areas - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid114 (Box 3, Item 51)
  - SIDI N.B.G. Sea Moon Maurice Bishop Grenada - Audio Cassette, March 25, 1979; cuid115 (Box 3, Item 52)
  - Grenada - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid116 (Box 3, Item 53)
  - Untitled - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid117 (Box 3, Item 54)
  - 1 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid118 (Box 3, Item 55)
  - 9 - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid119 (Box 3, Item 56)
  - Lecture on West Indies in T.C. Ian - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid120 (Box Shared University Archives 098, Item 57)
  - Transfer of Tape A - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid121 (Box Shared University Archives 098, Item 58)
  - Sea Moon, Kereusk, Grant, Bernard Coard, Maurice Bishop 5 Recorded (partially) from radio broadcasts in St. Ancia - Audio Cassette, March 25, 1979; cuid122 (Box Shared University Archives 098, Item 59)
    On tape: "Recorded (partially) from radio broadcasts in St. Ancia; March 25, 1979"
  - La Bamba Demonstration Tape - Audio Cassette, undated; cuid123 (Box Shared University Archives 098, Item 60)
  - The Drums of Vodou Featuring Frisner Augustin - Audio Cassette, 1994; cuid124 (Box Shared University Archives 098, Item 61)
    On tape: promotional copy for ABA '94; White Cliffs Media"
  - Maurice Bishop - Audio Cassette, March 25, 1979; cuid125 (Box Shared University Archives 098, Item 62)
    On tape: March 25, 1979"
  - Caribbean Poets, Brooklyn Museum, March 16, 1985; cuid126 (Box Shared University Archives 098, Item 63)
    Ontape: "3/16/85"